Akshay Siddhpura

Senior Software Engineer (Blackbuck - Zinka Logistics)

Bangalore | +91-9099063892 | adsiddhpura@hotmail.com

akshay-siddhpura.github.io in linkedin.com/in/akshaysiddhpura/



Profile

Software developer with **5.6 years** of thorough experience in designing and implementing software applications and frameworks with a talent of solving problems analytically, well versed in managing team members and also to be a team player to ensure timely completion of all deadlines.

Professional Experience

Blackbuck (Trucking platform)

June 2019 - Present

- Leading the E-commerce flow of the GPS module, which involves implementing large complex business flows.
- Designed & implemented subscription and auto-deduction features of various GPS plans.
- Implemented activation flow of IoT Devices by integration with the third party.
- Designed & implemented state machine for the order Management system of GPS device, worked on end to end flow.
- Migrated monolithic architecture to microservice architecture.
- Contributed in MIS module for acquiring and retaining customers on the platform.

Oracle India Pvt. Ltd.

Oct 2017 - May 2019

Human Capital Management - Fusion Applications Developer

Oracle Fusion Applications are enterprise resource planning software applications from Oracle Corporation. It is distributed across various product families; including financial management, human capital management, customer relationship management, supply chain management. Oracle Fusion Human Capital Management is a complete suite of HR products that offers the complete spectrum of HR functions like person management, employment management, payroll, absences, work-structures, etc. integrated together in a seamless manner.

- Implemented various task flows of Person module functionalities using JAVA/ADF
- Spearheaded integration project of Address component and make component easily customizable for other teams and products.
- Redesign and implemented Person Module for mobile compatibility and integrated task flow in Java/ADF

TATA Consultancy Services, India

Jun 2014 - Oct 2017

Commercial Taxation System - Module lead

- A key member of the Framework Team for Taxation Projects and Module Lead for Payment & Registration modules for one of the Taxation Projects.
 - o Performed Third-party integration with 10 banks.
 - Worked with the framework team to develop various components of TCS's taxation framework on technologies like J2EE, Spring, Hibernate.
- Lead for the customized Dashboard framework, its architecture depended on Materialized Views in Enterprise DB and custom components developed with SQL DB interaction using JSON (mainly for Personalized User Profiles).
 - Reports were custom generated from a stored procedure or Materialized View.
 - Rendered reports were configured in terms of columns, parameters, and various filters after customization of Data Tables.
 - Implemented Configurable multi-data source structure for Near site and Far Site database that uses
 the transnational database for login and audit purpose and relied on
 on far site databases for heavy procedures and queries.
- $\bullet\,$ Customized Bootstrap Framework as per the needs of Taxation Projects
 - Implemented configurations to change Bootstrap Themes (UI elements, Component and their Responsiveness) as per the requirement

Education

Skills

- Programming: Java, J2EE, Python.
- Frameworks: Spring Boot, Apache Kafka, ADF.
- Web: JSON, REST API, Bootstrap-css
- Tools: IntellJ, Eclipse, Jdeveloper, Git, Tortoise SVN, Jupyter Notebook, ADE.
- Cloud Platform: Amazon Web Services(AWS)
- Data Management: MySQL, Oracle (10g), Elastic search, Kibana, Redis
- Other: Apache Tomcat, JBoss, WebLogic.

Certifications

- Python For Data Science March 2018 -by IBM
- Workshop of Apparel Recommendation Engine for Amazon clothing.
- Attended training for Application Development Framework
- Conducted technical training of Dashboard framework and Bootstrap framework across TCS Govt.ISU.

Achievements

- "Best Practice Award" across TCS India for development of Dashboard Framework.
- Awarded as "ILP Kudos" during corporate & technical training at TCS.
- Winner of Codejam competition at the Techfest of DDU University.

Personal passions

A case study on "Apparel Recommendation Engine": A recommendation engine which recommends similar apparel products in ecommerce using product descriptions and Images, without using any ML algorithm

A case study on "Credit card similar transactions": Data exploration and understanding based on similarities

A case study on "Fund analysis": Data exploration to find best country for investment.